Preliminary Guide to the Neal E. Miller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory
  - Dallas 10/4-7/81 [Cardiovascular Conference, 1981 (Box 25)
  - Douglas College, 11/4/81 [Rutgers, NJ - Talk on how the brain affects the health of the body], 1981 (Box 25)
  - Ramapo College, 10/28/81 [Master Lecture}, 1981 (Box 25)
  - APA Meetings, Aug. '84 [Symposium on Behavioral Approaches to Rehab/Health Psychology], 1981 (Box 25)
  - Stress Conference - Detroit 5/31/81, 1981 (Box 25)
  - Hershey [Medical Center] seminar - Lecture on biofeedback and behavioral medicine - 4/4/81, 1981 (Box 25)
  - American Psychosomatic Society - Talk on "Behavioral Models of Disease Etiology" 3/81, 1981 (Box 25)
  - C.W. Post [Center], Long Island University, 2/81 -[Talk on how the brain affects the health of the body], 1981 (Box 25)
  - Regrets 1980-1981 [NEM unable to give talks, etc.] (Box 25)
  - Healing Brain [Symposium] - NYC 12/7/80, 1980 (Box 25)
  - AABT [Association for Advancement of Behavioral Therapy convention, invited address on how the brain affects the health of the body] - 11/23/80, 1980 (Box 25)
  - Budapest - To Take [Materials NEM took to International Congress of Physiological Sciences, Hungary, June 1980 (Box 25)
  - XXII International Congress of Psychology, Leipzig, July 1980 (Box 25)
  - "Leipzig - Feb. 15 Deadline"[Materials by others relating to above Congress], 1980 (Box 25)
  - Regrets 1979-1980 [NEM unable to give talks, etc.] (Box 25)
  - APA 1980 [Talk, "Relating Classic Concepts of General Psychology to Behavioral Medicine" (Box 25)
  - Cataldo Conference 4/24,25/90 [Talk for Conference on Behavioral Intervention in Neurology, Johns Hopkins], 1980 (Box 25)
  - China - Oct. 1980 [NEM headed delegation of 5 profs to visit People's Republic of China for 2 weeks. - Director of Chinese Institute of Psychology suggested he speak on (1) effects of stress and coping and (2) role of learning in neurosis and psychotherapy] (Box 25)
  - China #2 [more correspondence related to above], 1980 (Box 25)
  - Drafts for China [NEM's lectures for above], 1980 (Box 25)
  - BSA [Biofeedback Society of America] Annual Meeting 3/7/80 - [Keynote speech on Experimental-Clinical Symbiosis], 1980 (Box 25)
  - National Geographic TV - ["Mysteries of the Mind" program], 1978 (Box 25)
  - Regrets 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - ARNMD[ Mtg, Association for Research in Nervous and Mental Disease, Inc.], Dec. '79, NYC, 1979 (Box 25)
  - LaSalle [College], 10/21/79 - Honorary Degree, 1979 (Box 25)
  - Australia [13th Annual Conference of Australian Psychological Society - NEM hosted general discussion session, spoke on Visceral Learning and Biofeedback, 8/15/78; gave keynote address at Newcastle, 8/27/78], 1978 (Box 25)
  - Duke UMC [University Medical Center] - Grand Rounds - 2 talks: Behavioral Medicine, and Visceral Learning and Homeostasis - 3/27/80, 1980 (Box 25)
  - Behavioral Mod. Group Los Angeles 10/12/79 [So. California Conference on Behavioral Modification - NEM talk on behavioral and psychoanalytical theories], 1979 (Box 26)
  - Regrets 1977-1978 (Box 26)
  - St. Francis [College] 6/8/78 [NE keynote speaker for Biofeedback Seminar], 1978 (Box 26)
  - Stress (Wengert) NYC Dec. '77-May '78 [Conference on Stress and Behavioral Medicine, Chicago, 5/'78], 1978 (Box 26)
  - Johnson and Johnson 5/25/77 [Talk on Biofeedback], 1977 (Box 26)
  - University of Maine, May 1977 [Colloquium] (Box 26)
  - Colorado State University Phone Interview, 1977 (Box 26)
  - Yale Conference on Behavioral Medicine, 2/5-6/77 [NEM presentation on history of behavioral medicine], 1977 (Box 26)
  - San Francisco 1/22-23/77 [Symposium on Biofeedback, Meditation, and Self-Regulatory Therapies at UC-San Francisco], 1977 (Box 26)
  - NY Heart Association 1/10/77 - [Seminar on cardiovascular aspects of biofeedback], 1977 (Box 26)
  - Regrets 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - APA - 9/3-7/76, Wash, D.C. [Symposium on non-pharmacological approaches to hypertension], 1976 (Box 26)
  - Japan - Hirai/Hama [correspondence w. H. Hirai and H.Hama, etc., concerning NEM's visit and talks] 2976, 1976 (Box 26)
  - Schlosberg Colloquium, Brown University 5/20/76, 1976 (Box 26)
  - Norristown 4/22/76 [Talk at State Hospital re Biofeedback], 1976 (Box 26)
  - Florida Atlantic University 3/18/76 [Distinguished Lecture Series], 1976 (Box 26)
  - Johns Hopkins Centennial 3/15/76 [Talk on Psychosomatic Effects of Learning], 1976 (Box 26)
  - BRS [Biofeedback Research Society], Colo. Springs, 2/27-3/2/76 [Keynote Address - Seventh Annual Meeting], 1976 (Box 26)
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons [Columbia U.] 2/5/76 [Talk on Biofeedback], 1976 (Box 26)
  - NY Medical College, 1/7/76 [Talk on recent advances in Psychiatry], 1976 (Box 26)
  - Albert Einstein 12/5/75 [College of Medicine - Talk for Department of Psychiatry on current status of Biofeedback], 1975 (Box 26)
  - Towson College (Baltimore, MD) 3/15-16/75 [Talks on Stress and Biofeedback], 1975 (Box 26)
  - CIBA and Soc. for Psychosomatic Research - London, 10/27-31/75 [Lecture and discussion on Learning, Emotion, and Physical Symptoms], 1975 (Box 26)
  - Regrets 1974-1975 (Box 26)
  - U. Cincinnati 5/75 [?] [Distinguished Visiting Lecturer for 1975] (Box 26)
  - American Academy of Neurology 5/1/75 [Wartenberg Lecture at annual meeting], 1975 (Box 26)
  - VA [Veterans Administration} Keynote [Address] 4/9-11/75 [on Applications of Learning and Biofeedback at Medicine and Psychiatry], 1975 (Box 26)
  - American Association For the Advancement of Science [American Association for the Advancement of Science] Jan. 1975 [1/2 day program on Brain Functions and Physical Well-Being, arr. by NEM] (Box 26)
  - Utah - Dec. 74 [Brigham Young University], 1974 (Box 26)
  - International Congress on Physiological Sciences, New Delhi, India, Oct. 21-26, 1974 [Talk on Visceral Control through Training - NEM went with E. Hilgard] (Box 26)
  - Baku and Moscow Oct. 74 [Proceedings of Satellite Symposium Emotions and Visceral Functions - NEM on Effects of Learning... Visceral Functions], 1974 (Box 26)
  - Canadian Psychiatric Association 10/1-4/74 [Talk on Effects of Learning on Emotions and Psychosomatic Symptoms], 1974 (Box 26)
  - APA 1974 - Aggression [NEM Chairman of program called Aggression and War: An Interdisciplinary Perspective] (Box 26)
  - Mayo Clinic 5/16-17/74 [Symposium on Biological Basis of Behavior - NEM talk on Interdisciplinary Approach to Study of Behavior], 1974 (Box 26)
  - Regrets 1973-1974 (Box 26)
  - Anshen 2/22/74 [Columbia U. seminar on Nature of Man - talk on how psychological factors can influence bodily processes], 1974 (Box 26)
  - 4th Symposium on Behavior Modification, Mexico, 1/16-18/74 [talk on Psychosomatic Effects of Learning], 1974 (Box 26)
  - Regrets 1972-1973 (Box 26)
  - Bell Labs 11/28/73 [Talk to General Research Colloquium on Facts and Fantasies of Biofeedback], 1973 (Box 26)
  - St. Lawrence University [Talks for dedication of Psychology Bldg. - on Teaching an Understanding of Science and How Learning May affect Psychosomatic Symptoms], 1973 (Box 26)
  - Rehab. Conference (Zaretsky) [NYU Medical Center Conference on Research Utilization - talk on using research for rehab. of the disabled and disadvantaged] 5/31-6/1/73, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Montefiore [Hospital and Medical Center] 5/29/73 [Talk to Grand Rounds of Psychiatry Department], 1973 (Box 26)
  - University of Virginia Medical Ctr. 4/27/73 [Talk on psychosomatic effects of learning] + P. Morris [Philip Morris Company - NEM spoke at dedication of their Research Center], 1973 (Box 26)
  - 20th Anniversary [Science Symposium] Philip Morris 4/26/73 [Talk on Implications of Visceral Learning to Theories of Stress and Anxiety], 1973 (Box 26)
  - NIMH - Biofeedback Advisory Mtg., Bethesda, MD, 4/11-12/73, 1973 (Box 26)
  - City College of CUNY 4/11/73 [lecture on How Psychological Factors Can Affect Bodily Processes], 1973 (Box 26)
  - Downstate Medical Center [SUNY] [Talk on Visceral Learning and Biofeedback to Psychiatry Department Grand Rounds] 4/4/73, 1973 (Box 26)
  - NIMH Washington, DC, School of Psychiatry, 3/9/73 [Talk on Biofeedback], 1973 (Box 26)
  - Philadelphia - 2/5-6/73 [Neurobiology Lecture, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Yale 1/5/73 [Department of Psychiatry talk on Stress], 1973 (Box 26)
  - Electroenceph: NYC 11/29/72 [Kershman Lecture, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Society for Psychophysiological Research - Boston, 11/9/72 [Lecture on Biofeedback] (Box 26)
  - NYU - Fullbright 11/7/72, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Association for the Advancement of Behavior - NYC 10/7/72 - Panel discussing application of behavioral methods to psychosomatic problems, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Psychology XXth Int. [Congress of] Tokyo 1972 [Talk on the Psychosomatic Effects of Learning] (Box 26)
  - CUMC [Cornell University Medical College] 5/31/72 [Lecture on Autonomic Learning], 1972 (Box 26)
  - Yale - Sigma Xi 5/5/72 [Talk on Psychological Factors in Psychosomatic Symptoms, 1972 (Box 26)
  - EPA 1972 - 2/29 [Eastern Psychological Association, 43rd annual mtg. - Invited lecture Experiments on Psychosomatic Interactions (Box 26)
  - Rochester [University of] 4/7/72 [General talk to Psychology Department on Learning by... Visceral Organs and another talk on Chemical Stimulation of the Brain for formation of Rochester's Society for Neuroscience - NEM Pres. of national Society for Neuroscience], 1972 (Box 26)
  - Senior Fullbright - Rockefeller University - 3/15/72 [talk on Learning by the Heart and Other Visceral Organs to Senior Fullbright Scholars], 1972 (Box 26)
  - American College of Neuropsychopharmacology - Los Vegas, 1/18-21/72 [panel on Neurophysiological, Internal Environment, and Learning Theory Viewpoints of Mental Illness - NEM giving learning theory model], 1972 (Box 26)
  - Cigarette Smoking Conference 1/12-16/72 [NEM discussant in panel on motivation sponsored by Philip Morris Research Center], 1972 (Box 26)
  - Regrets 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Dr. Taub - Summary of Research, 1997 [by C.L.Edwards, Biofeedback; Taub receives. Distinguished Scientist Award for 1998] (Box 27)
  - Taub - Summary of recent work - 1996 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Transcoop Travel Grant 12/96, 1996 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Articles co-authored with NEM, 1993-1994 [#258, 261] (Box 27)
  - Taub - Society for Neuroscience Program - 1996 (Box 27)
  - Taub - General correspondence, 1984-1994 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Nomination for AAS Award, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Taub, Possible Awards
  - Taub - Rehab. Research
  - Taub - Scientific Publications
  - Taub -Sciencearticle (April 1991) [Later became #258 on Learned Nonuse] (Box 27)
  - Taub Case - Trial #1 - 1981 [Note: Rest of box 27 deals with case of Silver Spring Monkeys - attempt of animal activists, esp. Alex Pacheco of PETA to ruin Dr. Taub and NEM and others' attempts to defend him. - I've ordered chronology to make more sense.] (Box 27)
  - Taub - NEM's letters in defense of, 1981-1982 (Box 27)
  - Taub case #2 - Trial de novo - 1982 - Box 1 (Box 27)
  - Taub case #2 - Trial de novo - 1982 - Box 2 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Loss of [NIH] Grant because of case, 1982 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Trials, Citations + Brenner, Pre-trial Discovery (Box 27)
  - Taub case, 1983 (Box 27)
  - Taub on the Taub Case, 1983-1991 (Box 27)
  - NIH [Wyngaarden] vs. Taub, 1983-1986 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - 1984-1985 (Box 27)
  - Taub case, 1986 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - NEM letter to G. Bauer re, 1987 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - 1988-1989 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - NEM letter to Dr. Perry re, 1989 (Box 27)
  - Taub -NY Timesarticle re, + NEM's response, 1990 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - 1990-1991 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - Jon Franklin wanted to write book, threatened, 1991 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - New Yorker article + NEM's letter, 1993 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - 1996 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - Brenner's legal notes, 1991 (Box 27)
  - Taub case - Good chronology of case [Silver Spring incident], defense of Taub by E.E. Coons] (Box 27)
  - Taub - False Statements about lab by A. Pacheco PETA (Box 27)
  - Taub - Autopsy Report Info, 1981-1983 (Box 27)
  - Taub - P. Hand and A. Morrison investigation of amputation, 1984 (Box 27)
  - [From Taub] - ALF's description of University of Pennsylvania, naming A. Pacheco as the reporter's liaison with the ALF (Animal Liberation Front), 1986 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Caretaker's Absence, 1981 (Box 27)
  - Taub - Work on Phantom Limbs, 1995 (Box 27)
  - Advisory Committee on Animals in Research and Teaching [ACART], 1987-1993 (Box 28)
  - Adam. Georgy, 1971-1985 (Box 28)
  - Brucker[, Bernard] Thesis, 1977 [NEM cosponsored, thesis on learned voluntary control of systolic blood pressure by spinal cord injury patients] (Box 28)
  - Scoliosis
    - Patients, 1985-1986 (Box 28)
    - General, 1985-1993 (Box 28)
    - Therapists, 1985 (Box 28)
    - Inquiries [1977-1985] (Box 28)
    - Device - Patent [1975-1980] (Box 28)
    - Device Data and Consent Forms to Patients [1977-1978] (Box 28)
    - Correspondence w. Dr. Niels Birbaumer [Germany, 1978-1985] (Box 28)
    - Correspondence, photos of devices, and articles, 1973-1981] (Box 28)
    - by W. Miltner, Taub report on, 1997 (Box 28)
  - G. Morrow - Reprints on treating nausea in cancer patients, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints - #1-#3 (Box 28)
  - Cowings, Patricia [Whole box is on meetings at NASA or correspondence w. Patricia Cowings of NASA and materials she has sent NEM, since for years he mentored her, collaborated with her on space motion sickenss rehab.], 1971-1998 (Box 29)
  - Cowings -Curriculum Vitae (Box 29)
  - Cowings - Photos of Devices (Box 29)
  - Cowings - Undated Mss. (Box 29)
  - Comroe and Dripps, Science article, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Comroe and Dripps - NSF Innovations [includes "Top Ten Clinical Advances, 1945-1975" (Box 30)
  - Biofeedback Co-operative Project, includes Epilepsy, 1982-1985 (Box 30)
  - [Rest of Box 30 has red numbers on each folder, such as #87 - These stand for the chronological numbers of Dr. Miller's publications - Each folder has correspondence on authors and number of article, etc.] Steinbaum and Miller, 1964 - #87 (Box 30)
  - Stricker and Miller, 1965 - #90 (Box 30)
  - Quartermain, Paolino, and Miller, Science - Retrograde amnesia, #93, 1965 (Box 30)
  - Barry, Etheredge, and Miller - #94, 1965 (Box 30)
  - Coons, Levak and Miller, Science 1965 - #95 (Box 30)
  - Wolf, Dahl and Miller - 1965, #96 (Box 30)
  - Wolf, American Journal of Physiology, #96, 1965 (Box 30)
  - [Miller:] "Some Animal Experiments Pertinent to Combining Psychotherapy with Drug Therapy" - #97, 1965 (Box 30)
  - Davis and Miller - "...Printing Counter" - #99, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Quartermain and Miller, 1966 - #101 (Box 30)
  - Chien - Carbachol and ADH - #114 - 1968 (Box 30)
  - Miller - Dollard Festschrift, 1970 (Moscow paper, updated) - #137 (Box 30)
  - Carmona et al., Psychosomatic Medicine, #150, 1973 (Box 30)
  - Editorial [NEM] New England Journal of Medicine, #158, 1974 (Box 30)
  - Biofeedback Annual - Preface, #160 - 1973 (Box 30)
  - NEM [Essay] for Worth Publishers, 1975 - #162 (Box 30)
  - NEM - Chapter for book [ Experimental Approaches to Psychopathology, Kietzman et al., eds.] - #163, 1974 (Box 30)
  - CTP II [NEM Article, "Applications of Learning and Biofeedback to Psychiatry and Medicine"] - #164, 1975 (Box 30)
  - [Chapter on voluntary control of heart rate, etc., for] American College of Cardiology [book], 1973-1975 - #165 (Box 30)
  - Blizard et al. [article forBiological Psychology], 1975, #166 (Box 30)
  - VA [Vets' Administration] Keynote, 4/9/75 [20th annual Conference, V.A. Studies in Mental Health and Behavioral Sciences] - #169, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Konorski Festschrift [Paper on Learning, Stress, and Psychosojmatic Symptoms - #172, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Kittay - Submitted 5/23/75 [NEM paper "The Role of Learning in Physiological Responses to Stress", given at Kittay Scientific Foundation, 3rd International Symposium, 4/6-8/1975 - #173, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Master Lecture APA 1974, revised July '76 - #174, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Pickering and Miller, PJCS - #176, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Miller and Dworkin chap. [in Biofeedback: Theory and Research, Schwartz and Beatty, eds.] - #177, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Dworkin and Miller chap. [in Biofeedback: Theory and Research, Schwartz and Beatty, eds.] - #178, 1976 (Box 30)
  - Physiology in Medicine [part of New England Journal of Medicine - article by Miller and Dworkin - #179], 1977 (Box 30)
  - Almy - shorter version #182 [ms. on Effect of Learning on Gastrointestinal Functions, for book edited by T. Almy], 1977 (Box 30)
  - Almy book [original version] - #182, 1977 (Box 30)
  - Miller and Brucker - Tubingen - #189 [pub. chapter in Birbaumer ed., Biofeedback and Self-Regulation ], 1979 (Box 31)
  - Selye chapter [in book Guide to Stress Research ] - #201, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Pfaff Book - #213 - Chapter on Motivation, Learning and Performance, 1982 (Box 31)
  - Stony Brook Keynote [Symposium on Clinical Biofeedback - Efficacy and Mechanism, May 1980, at SUNY-Stony Brook - talk on Biofeedback, became chap. in Clinical Biofeedback..., White and Tursky, eds.], 1982 (Box 31)
  - Stress[-Induced] Analgesia [International Conference on], 5/1-3/85 - [NEM panelist in Symposium, presented Morality and Humaneness of Animal Research on Stress and Pain, which became publication #238], 1985 (Box 31)
  - Stunkard review 1/12/79 [NEM's review of A. Stunkard, for The Pain of Obesity for Biofeedback and Self-Regulation ] - #200, 1979 (Box 31)
  - NATO - Coping and Health [Levine and Ursin, eds. - NEM book chapter, from talk at NATO Conference, Bellagio, Italy, March 1980 - became article #197] (Box 31)
  - Soviet Exchange, Irvine [US-USSR Symposium on Neurophysiological Mechanisms..., April '78 - Talk on Different Ways in which Learning is involved in Homeostasis became book chapter, article #202, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Soviet Exchange, 5/18/19/81 [US/USSR Symposium on Hypertension. NEM talk "Effects of Learning on Hypertension" became article #216] (Box 31)
  - Article for Comprehensive Textbook of Psychiatry III, on application of learning and biofeedback to psychiatry and medicine - #199, 1980 (Box 31)
  - Ms. "Psychosomatic Effects of Learning", chapter in Myer and Brady book, public. #187, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Diabetes - Biofeedback Project 1980 (Box 31)
  - Psychology 107 - Abstracts [NEM course materials], 1940-1941 (Box 31)
  - Psychology 122 Mid-Term and Final Exams, 1953, 1961, 1962, 1964 (Box 31)
  - NEM's exam questions on 5"x8" cards, 1953? (Box 31)
  - NEM - Notes on the Concept of Drive and Its Relationship to Reinforcement - 1947 [for Psych 122 class, original version and another revised in 1959] (Box 31)
  - NEM - Notes on the Psychology of Teaching Students to Fly, 1947? (Box 31)
  - NEM - The Role of Motivation in Learning [also for Psychology course 122, at Yale], 1950's? (Box 31)
  - NEM - Social Science and the Art of Advertising [Institute of Human Relations, Yale, Department of Psychology - given at meeting, 1949] (Box 31)
  - Meehl and Miller Correspondence, 1951 (Box 31)
  - Mimeographed materials, midterms, final exams, etc., for Psychology 122, 122A, and 122B, 1949-1966 (Box 32)
  - Mimeographed materials, midterms, final exams, etc., for Psychology 122, 122A, and 122B, various years, and papers on Psychology 10A, 55A+B, 91, 100, 101A, and 118 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence and papers on Clark Hull's Seminar, 1938-1942; Department seminar, 1937-1942. (Box 34)
  - National Academy of Sciences folders - 1955-1959; folders for nomination of new members, ending with separate folders for vitae of 37 scientists, including Jean Mayer and Jean Piaget (Box 34)
  - Synthetic sex-hormone data, 1938; NEM paper on administering hormone; example of newspaper articles on discovery of hormone and several folders of people requesting information on the hormone, and data on patients administered hormone. (Box 35)
  - Research and Development Board [NEM consultant to Pentagon, 1951-1953] (Box 35)
  - Fear and Courage Studies: Plan to Study Fear and Courage [w. John Dollard] and government response; Interviews with veterans and with cadets, 1942-1944 (Box 35)
  - Aggression system - Lecture Notes, 1937 (Box 35)
  - Saccharin experiments, Murray and Roberts, 1951, '54 (Box 35)
  - Data for Brain Stimulation Studies w. Cats, 1953-1954 (Box 35)
  - [General folders having to do with experiments] - Apparatus Construction, 1959-1960; Blood Pressure; Electrode Technique; ENDO Labs caffeine data for Barry/Ziombardo; Experimental animals - sources; Research Plans 1950-1951, 1951-1952, 1958-1960 + Summer Research 1960; Stress technique; Tests, Standardized; Visceral Instrumentation (Box 36)
  - [Folders for specific experiments]: Experiments on Air Drinking; Alcohol; Aggression; Anxiety, Childhood; Approach-Avoidance; Aviation Research; Balloon Exp. on bar pressing; Child Research; Conditioning of GSR; Conflict {several experiments, became book}; Continuity-Discontinuity; Disappearance of an avoidance response; Displacement; Drive and Drive-Reduction; Extinction; Fear; Gastric Fistula Operation; Generalization of Conflict; Generalization of Secondary Reinforcement; Genetics and Social Behavior; Gesell Exam. for Infant Development (Box 36)
  - [More folders for specific experiments]: Experiments on Habit Strength; Hoarding; Hunger; Hunger and Thirst; Hypothalamic Studies; Imitation; Intraventricular Injection of Water; Heartrate Learning; Homeostasis; Toxin Study {E.J. Holmes} (Box 37)
  - [Folders on organizations NEM belonged to]: Institute for Advancement of Health, 1982-1983 + 1984-1985; IBRO/UNESCO (International Brain Research Organization - several folders, 1964-1979); International Physiological Congress; International Congress of Psychology, Montreal 1954 [w. NEM paper] and Moscow 1966; International Association for Study of Higher Nervous Activity; International Organization of Psychophysiology; International Society for Research on Aggression; International Symposium on Psychotropic Drugs, Milan 1957; Jackson Lab, Board of Trustees (Box 37)
  - London, Royal Society of; McArthur Foundation; Microelectrode Recording; Narcotics Registry Correspondence; Narcotics 1963; National Medal of Science [correspondence on nominating others, incl. exchange between NEM and B.F. Skinner]; NAS-NRC {National Academy of Sciences - National Research Council - several folders}; National Science Foundation; NIMH and NIH folders -{National Institutes of Health and National Institute of Mental Health} (Box 38)
  - Eastman Kodak files [re NEM's book on Graphic Communications - takes up 1/2 box] Rest of box is Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1974 and 1975-1976, alpha by author (Box 39)
  - Correspondence
    - A, B, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - C, D, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - E, F, G, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - H, I, J, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - K, L, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - M, N, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - O, P, Q, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - R, S, T, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - U, V, W, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - X, Y, Z, 1969-06-01-1972-09-20 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Miller from Julius Segal, 1985-07-01 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Audiovisual material
    - Miller, Roberts, and Delgado - learning motivated by electrical stimulation of brain (ESB) - cats, 1.0 (Box 41)
    - Kohler negative, 1.0 (Box 42)
    - Print of Kohler film (on Miller), 1.0 (Box 43)
    - Platt (done at Florida State), 1.0 (Box 44)
    - New print, 1.0 (Box 62)
      Scope and Contents
      Label includes a content list: 1. Cat drinks; NBL; 2. Cat licks bars; 3. Two rats eat to ESB; 4. Rat gnaws stick; 5. Rat pushes panel; 6. Inject ACH; 7. Rats eat and drink; 8. Stationary mother, monkey crouches; 9. Moving mother, monkey explores; 10. Cat attacks rat